<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on Smooth as consumption</title>
    <link>/categories/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on Smooth as consumption</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Acerbi &amp; Szekely Unconditional Expected Shortfall Test</title>
      <link>/posts/expectedshortfalltest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/expectedshortfalltest/</guid>
      <description>Python implementation of the Direct Expected Shortfall Test of Acerbi and Szekely (2014).
#This code creates our distribution of the difference in ginis by bootstrapping different homes from the original sample (as many as in the original sample, with replacement). #This code should not be executed if one already has the data, takes a lot of time, so we could load the already computed data.df &amp;lt;- data.table(df)set.seed(666)R &amp;lt;- 1000000diferencia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test of Correct Specification of Conditional Densities</title>
      <link>/posts/rossitest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/rossitest/</guid>
      <description>#This code creates our distribution of the difference in ginis by bootstrapping different homes from the original sample (as many as in the original sample, with replacement). #This code should not be executed if one already has the data, takes a lot of time, so we could load the already computed data.df &amp;lt;- data.table(df)set.seed(666)R &amp;lt;- 1000000diferencia.de.gini &amp;lt;- vector(mode = &amp;quot;numeric&amp;quot;, length = R)for(i in 1:R){remuestra &amp;lt;- df[sample(.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzles and the Behavioural New Keynesian Model</title>
      <link>/posts/determinacy_gabaix_new_keynesian_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/determinacy_gabaix_new_keynesian_model/</guid>
      <description>Herein I conduct similar policy experiments to those of Carlstrom et al. (2012) with a Behavioural New Keynesian (BNK) model, instead of the standard New Keynesian model (only) or a sticky information model. The BNK model does a good job of solving previous issues with the standard model (as already noted by Gabaix).
All of this work is already, explicitly or implicitly, in the cited articles, so I wouldn’t claim to show anything new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incidencia distributiva del gasto en formación universitaria en Cataluña</title>
      <link>/posts/enric_despesa_universitaria/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/enric_despesa_universitaria/</guid>
      <description>¿Como afecta, sólo en sus efectos más inmediatos, el gasto en formación universitaria a la distribución de renta de los hogares en Cataluña?
Enric, con quien tuve el placer de coincidir durante mis estudios en la Universidad Pompeu Fabra, se formula esta pregunta en su trabajo de final de grado. También, le agradezco enormemente que compartiera sus datos conmigo, facilitando enormemente producir este post.
Los resultados se pueden resumir en las dos primeras cifras de a Tabla 7, el coeficiente de Gini de la renta disponible, 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determinacy in a New Keynesian Model under a Money Growth Rule</title>
      <link>/posts/determinacy_new_keynesian_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/determinacy_new_keynesian_model/</guid>
      <description>This note derives the analytical conditions for determinacy in a canonical New Keynesian model under an exogenous path for the growth rate of the money supply. Under cash-when-I’m-done timing the model is always determinate while indeterminacy can arise with cash-in-advance timing.
FULL TEXT: See in “Projects”
Update: Now you can also find my presentation of the paper at the IV Navarra-Basque Country Macroeconomics Workshop.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La universitat gratuïta es ajudar els rics</title>
      <link>/posts/universitat_gratuita_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/universitat_gratuita_2/</guid>
      <description>Recentment s’ha publicat un article escrit per dos companys i jo mateix al diari Ara. El podeu llegir aquí.
També va aparèixer a la versió impresa del 11 de Gener de 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universitat gratuïta, un dret?</title>
      <link>/posts/universitat_gratuita_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/universitat_gratuita_1/</guid>
      <description>¿No tenen totes les persones un dret a a l’educació? ¿Tenim dret a rebre una formació universitària? ¿Existeixen eixes obligacions morals?
Em faig aquestes preguntes ja que aquestes són les realment importants, les de fons, les que determinen la visió del que ha de ser en la societat. Per a un anàlisis més moderat i pragmàtic recomano al lector fer una ullada a Universitat gratuïta: subvencionant els rics?, tot i que si considerem la formació universitària un dret, tal com pot ser la llibertat d’associació, el vot o el dret a socors l’anàlisi pragmàtic no l’afecta gaire.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>