<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Smooth as consumption</title>
    <link>/categories/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Smooth as consumption</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Acerbi &amp; Szekely Unconditional Expected Shortfall Test</title>
      <link>/posts/expectedshortfalltest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/expectedshortfalltest/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}Python implementation of the Direct Expected Shortfall Test of Acerbi and Szekely (2014).I don’t know of any implementation of such test in Python. The test has been implemented in MatLab. The backtesting of Expected Shortfall has long been a dificult task due to the lack of elicitibility. The test I’ve implemented is the second test of Acerbi and Szekely and it’s full details are in the reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzles and the Behavioural New Keynesian Model</title>
      <link>/posts/determinacy_gabaix_new_keynesian_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/determinacy_gabaix_new_keynesian_model/</guid>
      <description>Herein I conduct similar policy experiments to those of Carlstrom et al. (2012) with a Behavioural New Keynesian (BNK) model, instead of the standard New Keynesian model (only) or a sticky information model. The BNK model does a good job of solving previous issues with the standard model (as already noted by Gabaix).
All of this work is already, explicitly or implicitly, in the cited articles, so I wouldn’t claim to show anything new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incidencia distributiva del gasto en formación universitaria en Cataluña</title>
      <link>/posts/enric_despesa_universitaria/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/enric_despesa_universitaria/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}¿Como afecta, sólo en sus efectos más inmediatos, el gasto en formación universitaria a la distribución de renta de los hogares en Cataluña?
Enric, con quien tuve el placer de coincidir durante mis estudios en la Universidad Pompeu Fabra, se formula esta pregunta en su trabajo de final de grado. También, le agradezco enormemente que compartiera sus datos conmigo, facilitando enormemente producir este post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determinacy in a New Keynesian Model under a Money Growth Rule</title>
      <link>/posts/determinacy_new_keynesian_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/determinacy_new_keynesian_model/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}This note derives the analytical conditions for determinacy in a canonical New Keynesian model under an exogenous path for the growth rate of the money supply. Under cash-when-I’m-done timing the model is always determinate while indeterminacy can arise with cash-in-advance timing.
FULL TEXT: See in “Projects”
Update: Now you can also find my presentation of the paper at the IV Navarra-Basque Country Macroeconomics Workshop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>